Welcome to my studio today, my name is Lars Erik Robinson.
My name is Lars Arts All Around Art-tainment.
I'm a freelance illustrator.
Today we're going to talk about how to draw mountains.
I pre-sketched one here with little ink lines here how to show how to do it with watercolor.
I'm going to go ahead and get the gray blue onto my brush.
By doing that you take a little blue, maybe take a little part green, and never try to use black because when you use black it really tends to muddy it, so try to mix it in with some colors.
We'll take the side of our brush here and try to get that - if the sun's coming from this way, we'll get the shadow part of the mountain.
So it's kind of like a greenish blue color that you want to create, 'cause it creates that stone.
From the other end it could be more - you can try to get the yellow part of it, of the sun hitting it on that side.
Try to leave the tops of the white... and then we'll take a dark green.
So, an overcap of how you can do mountains.
Always try to think about where the sun's hitting it, and create the other side of it.
Maybe like a blueish green on that side, take your brush again, go down with streaks, like that, it will create the crevices in the mountain.
Clouds up there... if you want to create atmosphere in the sky, take your blue and clouds again... all right.
I hope that gives you all an idea of how to do mountains.
Keep on painting.
Go out there and make those landscapes and do those mountains.
Thank you so much.
Bye now.